A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Board of Pharmacy, 1886-2022.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Minutes of the Virginia Board of Pharmacy,
1886-2022.
The Library of Virginia
26537, 33426, 35157, 37955, 40124, 40320, 45477, 52117, 52308, 52962, 53864
Virginia. Dept. of Health Professions.
4.15 cubic feet; 17 v.; 1.14 gb.
Electronic records are available in the Reading Room at the Library of Virginia. Must make arrangements prior to viewing records.
These records are part of the Virginia Dept. of Health Professions record group (RG# 37)
Administrative Information
Arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
Accession 37955 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 02/20/2001.
Accession 40124 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 10/30/2002.
Accession 40320 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 01/27/2003.
Accession 45477 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 04/07/2011.
Accession 50101 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 08/26/2011.
Accession 52117 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 10/17/2017.
Accession 52308 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 02/27/2018.
Accession 52962 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 02/04/2020.
Accession 53864 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 04/13/2023.
Historical Information
Regulation of the health professions began late in the nineteenth century. On January 31, 1884, the General Assembly passed an act creating the Board of Medical Examiners to certify physicians for practice in Virginia. Two years later, acts establishing the Board of Dental Examiners (now the Board of Dentistry) and the Board of Pharmacy were passed by the General Assembly on February 26 and March 3, 1886, respectively. The Board of Embalmers (now the Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers) was created by an act passed on March 5, 1894, and the Board of Veterinary Examiners (now the Board of Veterinary Medicine) was established by an act passed on February 27, 1896. On May 1, 1903, the General Assembly created the Board of Graduate Nurses (now the State Board of Nursing), and on March 11, 1916, the Board of Optometry was established by legislative action.
The Dept. of Health Regulatory Boards was created by an act passed by the General Assembly on March 31, 1977, to provide administrative services to the health regulatory boards of the state. The boards continue to regulate their professions through the examination, licensing, and disciplining of the practitioners of health science. In 1986, the Dept. of Health Regulatory Boards became the Dept. of Health Professions. Its mission is to enhance the delivery of safe and competent health care by licensing qualified health care professionals, enforcing standards of practice, and providing information to both practitioners and consumers of health care services.
The Board of Pharmacy was created by an act of the General Assembly on March 3, 1886. The Board of Pharmacy regulates the practice of pharmacy and the manufacturing, dispensing, selling, distribution, processing, and disposal of drugs, cosmetics and devices within the Commonwealth. Also controls the character and standards of drugs, cosmetics and devices, and investigates complaints.
Scope and Content
Minutes, 1983-2022, documenting the meetings, activities, discussions, policy decisions and recommendations of the Virginia Board of Pharmacy. Includes minutes and agendas for formal board meetings, as well as for board retreats, formal hearings, informal conhearings, telephone conference calls, public hearings, and for committees and and other group meetings (Regulatory Committee, Special Conference Committee, Regulatory Advisory Panel, Innovative Pilot Program, Ad Hoc Committee for Pharmaceutical Processer Applications, Ad Hoc Committee for Routine Inspection Project, Ad Hoc Committee on Continuous Quality Improvement Plan, Ad Hoc Committee for On Hold Prescriptions, Drug Disposal Work Group, Protocols for Initiating Treatment (HB 1506) Work Group, Statewide Protocol Work Group, Additional Duties for Pharmacy Technician Work Group, and Unprofessional Conduct Pharmacy Conditions Work Group).
Also contains board meeting packets that include agendas, draft minutes, copies of minutes, and other meeting materials such as correspondence, budgets, guidance documentation, legislation, notes, presentations, public comments, press releases, regulations and reports.
Accession 53864 consists of Minutes, 2016-2022, in electronic format.
Contents List
- Minutes of the Virginia Board of Pharmacy, 1886-2022.
  - Minutes: Accession 37955 (1886-1901)., Extent: 2 v.
    Includes original, bound, handwritten minutes. May also include committee minutes and lists of pharmicists.
    - Minutes, 1886-1894. (Volume 1)
    - Minutes, 1894-1901. (Volume 2)
  - Minutes: Accession 26537 (1901-1937)., Extent: 7 v.
    Includes original, bound minutes. 1901-1912 are handwritten and 1912-1927 are typescript. May also include committee minutes, correspondence, reports, resolutions and lists of pharmicists.
    - Minutes, 1901-1907. (Volume 3)
    - Minutes, 1907-1912. (Volume 4)
    - Minutes, 1912-1916. (Volume 5)
    - Minutes, 1916-1922. (Volume 6)
    - Minutes, 1922-1926. (Volume 7)
    - Minutes, 1927-1932. (Volume 8)
    - Minutes, 1932-1937. (Volume 9)
  - Minutes: Accession 35157 (1937-1976)., Extent: 8 v.
    Includes original, bound minutes. May also include committee minutes, correspondence, reports, resolutions and lists of pharmicists.
    - Minutes, 1937-1942. (Volume 10)
    - Minutes, 1942-1947. (Volume 11)
    - Minutes, 1947-1952. (Volume 12)
    - Minutes, 1952-1956. (Volume 13)
    - Minutes, 1956-1960. (Volume 14)
    - Minutes, 1960-1968. (Volume 15)
    - Minutes, 1969-1973. (Volume 16)
    - Minutes, 1974-1976. (Volume 17)
  - Minutes: Accession 33426 (1976-1982)., Extent: .25 cu. ft. (1 box)
    Includes original, signed minutes, 1976-1982.
    - Minutes, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1977. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1978. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Accession 40124 (1983-1996)., Extent: .55 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    Includes original, signed minutes, 1983-1996.
    - Minutes, 1983. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1984. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1985. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1986. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1987. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1988. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1991. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 1992. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1993. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1996 Feb-July. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1996 Aug-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting packets: Accession 40320 (1995-1997)., Extent: .7 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    Includes board meeting packets, 1995 Dec-1997 June.
    - Full Board - Packet, 1995 Dec 13. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1996 Feb 13. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1996 Apr 18. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1996 June 13. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1996 Aug 20. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1996 Oct 17. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1996 Dec 12. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1997 Feb 20. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1997 Apr 8. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1997 June 10. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Full Board - Packet, 1997 Oct 9. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Accession 45477 (2004-2005)., Extent: .35 cu. ft. (1 box)
    Includes original, signed minutes, 2004 May-2005 Dec.
    - Minutes, 2004 May-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 2004 Oct-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 2005 Jan-May. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 2005 June-July. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 2005 Aug-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 2005 Oct-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Accession 50101 (2002-2004, 2006)., Extent: .35 cu. ft. (1 box)
    Contains original, signed Minutes, 2002 Apr, 2003 Sept-2004 Apr, and 2006 Jan-Dec.
    - Full Board, 2002 Apr 29. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Full Board, 2003 Sept 8. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Full Board, 2003 Nov 25. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2003 Dec 1. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2004 Jan 9. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Full Board, 2004 Jan 14. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Special Conference Committee, 2004 Jan 15. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Special Conference Committee, 2004 Feb 12. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Telephone Conference Call, 2004 Feb 12. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Full Board, 2004 Mar 4. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Telephone Conference Call, 2004 Mar 4. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Special Conference Committee, 2004 Mar 11. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Special Conference Committee, 2004 Mar 25. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Full Board, 2004 Apr 13. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Special Conference Committee, 2004 Apr 13. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2006 Jan 24. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Panel of the Board, 2006 Feb 8. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2006 Feb 28. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Full Board, 2006 Mar 8. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Telephone Conference Call, 2006 Mar 21. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Examination Committee, 2006 Mar 27. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Panel of the Board, 2006 Apr 4. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Telephone Conference Call, 2006 Apr 20. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Informal Conference Call, 2006 Apr 25. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Regulatory Review, 2006 May 15. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2006 May 31. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Full Board, 2006 June 5. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2006 June 27. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Informal Conference Call, 2006 June 29. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Ad Hoc Pedigree Committee, 2006 July 13. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Telephone Conference Call, 2006 Aug 10. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2006 Aug 29. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2006 Aug 31. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Full Board, 2006 Sept 27. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Telephone Conference Call, 2006 Oct 23. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Informal Conference Committee and Special Conference Committee, 2006 Oct 31. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Informal Conference Committee and Special Conference Committee, 2006 Dec 6. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2006 Dec 7. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Telephone Conference Call, 2006 Dec 13. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Minutes: Accession 52117 (2012).
    - Full Board, 2012. (Box 1)
    - Formal hearings, 2012. (Box 1)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2012. (Box 1)
    - Summary Suspension conference call, 2012. (Box 1)
    - Special Conference Committee, 2012. (Box 1)
    - Regulation Committee, 2012. (Box 1)
    - Pilot Informal Conference Committee, 2012. (Box 1)
  - Minutes and meeting packets: Accession 52308 (2012)., Extent: .55 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    Contains Board Packets, 2012, which include meeting agendas, copies of minutes, draft minutes, and other meeting materials. Some meeting files only contain an agenda, as indicated below.
    - Special Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Jan 10. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Special Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Feb 14. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Regulation Committee - Packet, 2012 Feb 16. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Pilot Informal Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Feb 16. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Special Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Mar 6. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Full Board - Packet, 2012. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Special Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Apr 30. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Formal hearing - Agenda, 2012 May 2. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Regulation Committee - Packet, 2012 May 2. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Special Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 May 15. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Full Board - Packet, 2012 June 12. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Special Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 June 29. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Formal hearing - Agenda, 2012 July 24. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Special Conference Committee and Informal Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Aug 22. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Full Board - Packet, 2012 Oct 1. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Special Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Oct 24. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Special Conference Committee and Informal Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Nov 6. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Special Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Oct 24. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Special Conference Committee and Informal Conference Committee - Agenda, 2012 Nov 6. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Pilot Informal Conference Committee, 2012 Nov 28. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Regulation Committee - Packet, 2012 Dec 11. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Full Board - Packet, 2012 Dec 12. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Special Conference Committee, 2012 Dec 18. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and meeting packets: Accession 52962 (1997-2011)., Extent: 1.4 cu. ft. (4 boxes)
    Includes copies of official, signed minutes, 1997 Oct-2004 June 8. Full Board minutes may also include committee meeting minutes. Also contains Board Packets, 2008 Sept-2011 Dec, which include agendas, copies of minutes, draft minutes, and other meeting materials.
    - Full Board, 1997 Oct 9. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Full Board, 1997 Dec 9. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Full Board, 1998 Feb 10. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Full Board, 1998 Apr 14. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Full Board, 1998 June 11. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Full Board, 1998 Aug 18. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Full Board, 1998 Oct 14. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Full Board, 1998 Dec 8. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Full Board, 1999 Feb 9. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Full Board, 1999 Apr 21. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Full Board, 1999 June 15. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Full Board, 1999 Aug 17. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Full Board, 1999 Oct 5. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Pharmacy Technicians, 1999 Nov 15. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Regulation Committee, 1999 Nov 15. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Full Board, 1999 Dec 14. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Full Board, 2000 Feb 15. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Full Board, 2000 Apr 12. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Regulation Committee, 2000 May 25. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Full Board, 2000 June 13. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Full Board, 2000 Aug 15. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Full Board, 2000 Oct 10. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Full Board, 2000 Nov 27. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Full Board, 2001 Feb 1. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Full Board, 2001 May 1. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Full Board, 2001 June 13. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Full Board, 2001 Aug 1. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Full Board, 2002 Feb 4. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2002 Feb 5. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Full Board, 2002 Apr 29. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Full Board, 2002 June 5. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Full Board, 2002 Aug 19. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2002 Aug 22. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Full Board, 2002 Sept 30. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Compounding, 2002 Oct 23. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Full Board, 2002 Dec 3. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2003 Jan 16. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Regulation Committee, 2003 Feb 26. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Regulation Committee, 2003 Mar 24. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Full Board, 2003 June 10. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Informal Conference Committee, 2003 Aug 18. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Review ACPE Request for Information, 2003 Aug 18. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Full Board, 2003 Nov 25. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Full Board, 2004 Jan 14. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Full Board, 2004 Feb 10. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Regulation Committee, 2004 Apr 22. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Full Board, 2004. (Box 2)
    - Full Board packet, 2008 Sept 3. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Regulation Committee packet, 2008 Nov 13. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Full Board packet, 2008 Dec 10. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Full Board packet, 2009 Mar 11. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Full Board packet, 2009 June 10. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Full Board packet, 2009 Sept 2. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Full Board packet, 2009 Dec 16. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Ad Hoc Committee packet, 2010 Feb 23. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Full Board packet, 2010 Mar 9. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Full Board packet, 2010 June 2. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Full Board packet, 2010 Sept 8. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Full Board packet, 2010 Dec 15. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Informal Conference Committee packet, 2011 Feb 9. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Full Board packet, 2011 Mar 9. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ad Hoc Committeee for On-Hold Prescriptions packet, 2011 May 17. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Pharmacy Inspections packet, 2011 May 18. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Continuous Quality Care Improvement Program packet, 2011 May 18. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Full Board packet, 2011 June 8. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Ad Hoc Committee for Continuous Quality Care Improvement Program packet, 2011. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Full Board packet, 2011 Sept 20. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Regulation Committee packet, 2011 Sept 29. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Full Board packet, 2011 Dec 14. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minutes and meeting packets: Accession 53864 (2016-2022).
    Pharmacy minutes, 2016-2022, are in electronic format (1.14 GB, 256 folders, 494 files). For file inventory for this accession, see: Inventory (53864).